[{"id": "59a1a3de12f2a7826b9b872a", "question": "Forty six represents the atonomic number of which element?", "answer": "Palladium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a95120565ad31a57c801", "question": "Xerxes the Great was the king of what empire?", "answer": "Achaemenid Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abac", "question": "What is the capital of the state of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec23f08dc25ca9e12ef634", "question": "In \"Gulliver's Travels\", what is the name of the flying island?", "answer": "Laputa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5b", "question": "What American poet wrote: \"The fog comes on little cat feet\"?", "answer": "Carl Sandburg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c96", "question": "In Charles Dickens' \"Oliver Twist\", what is the name of the man who trains boys to steal for him?", "answer": "Fagin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e3", "question": "What fruit comes in Chubby Gray and Jubilee variety?", "answer": "Watermelons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b9", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Cancer\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Crab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5df", "question": "What color is known as \"vert\" on a coat of arms?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3f7eff048f679a45ab5f", "question": "Which animal product does an ovo-vegetarian eat?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc199948005ec986edce6", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a543", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Ocean State\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb7", "question": "Which American statistician founded the institute of Public Opinion in 1935?", "answer": "Gallup", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2115a31a458464a93c441", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbce", "question": "In the card game Bridge, what is considered the highest of the four suits?", "answer": "Spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a992661d1b4d384d5d697", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" change its length from 30 minutes to 1 hour?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b4", "question": "Who on TV played Jeeves to Hugh Laurie's Bertie Wooster?", "answer": "Stephen Fry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b154", "question": "What 15th century Incan site was discovered in 1911 by Hiram Bingham?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4fa", "question": "What fabric derives its name from the French for \"cord of the king\"?", "answer": "Corduroy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c747", "question": "What element's chemical symbol are the letters \"Na\"?", "answer": "Sodium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b3", "question": "What lake was created when the Bagnell Dam was built across the Osage River?", "answer": "Lake of the Ozarks", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7dabff048f679a45abfb", "question": "Algophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e5f0cc2d274615ecf514531", "question": "Which Great Lake was known by the Ojibway as \"great water\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338caf", "question": "What artist pioneered Abstract Impressionism in 1948?", "answer": "Jackson Pollack", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078bab0eee65b76b9f266b", "question": "For what is Matthew Webb famous?", "answer": "He was the first man to swim the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3dd", "question": "The name \"Pterodactyl\" is based on a Greek phrase meaning what?", "answer": "Wing finger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e9b6fe83fe1f2a824beb", "question": "Queen Mary Tudor of England is better known to history by what name?", "answer": "Bloody Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f00601dd7bf43be5e7f9", "question": "In diner slang, what's a 50-50?", "answer": "Coffee with half and half", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad2", "question": "What is nephology the study of?", "answer": "Clouds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b5", "question": "What Shakespeare play if \"All the world's a stage\"?", "answer": "As You Like It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d0", "question": "Sound Navigation Ranging is better known as what?", "answer": "Sonar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc0b3ec223966ae8f885e", "question": "Where are all the adults in \"Children of the Corn\"?", "answer": "In the cornfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef60656ce05a3942286e4a", "question": "In what sport do you use the terms \"Chicken Salad\" and \"McTwist\"?", "answer": "Snowboarding", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16738f7c52aae91cc07b6", "question": "What is the capital of Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec4", "question": "Who was burnt at the stake by the English at Rouen on May 30th 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56e", "question": "What sport uses a \"pigskin\"?", "answer": "Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b12", "question": "What was the sub-title of the second Bridget Jones movie?", "answer": "The Edge of Reason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b1", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43b", "question": "What is the name for the soft white layer that forms on teeth?", "answer": "Plaque", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c5", "question": "In cocktail terminology, what does \"neat\" mean?", "answer": "A drink poured without water, ice or mixers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8a", "question": "What is the capital of Lesotho?", "answer": "Maseru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cd", "question": "Jaundice tends to turn one's skin, and sometimes the whites of the eyes, what color?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c817877e98cb977789dd", "question": "Which one of the New Seven Wonders of the World is located in Peru?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87e", "question": "What four notes are represented on the four strings of a ukulele?", "answer": "G, C, E, A", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a795", "question": "What is the capital of Trinidad and Tobago?", "answer": "Port of Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8d", "question": "In 1972, who became the first TV title character to get an abortion?", "answer": "Maude Findlay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd60740499cffc60b84238", "question": "Which European country was occupied by Britain from 1814 until 1964?", "answer": "Malta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c1b7877e98cb9777897b", "question": "What Roman building is known as the \"Square Colosseum\"?", "answer": "Palazzo della Civilt\u00e0 Italiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b414", "question": "Which significant beverage did John Pemberton invent in 1886?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0003b1cf6db9ac4808d0f", "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?", "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bf", "question": "In medicine, what does the abbreviation LASIK stand for?", "answer": "Laser-Assisted In Situ Keratomileusis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a097", "question": "\"Michelle\" and \"Julia\" are songs by which group?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338967", "question": "Who spent months rehearsing for \"My Fair Lady\" then had most of her singing dubbed by Marni Nixon?", "answer": "Audrey Hepburn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae82", "question": "During World War II, who was nicknamed The Desert Fox?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33c", "question": "Lock, Shock and Barrel were characters in which Halloween film?", "answer": "The Nightmare Before Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d7", "question": "Which is the most Northerly African country through which the Greenwich meridian passes?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940c", "question": "Who played Uncle Buck in the movie \"Uncle Buck\"?", "answer": "John Candy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fca", "question": "Which Canadian province is the setting for the novel \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde51e6c6c6b019850c9a92", "question": "In what nation were the Dead Sea Scrolls found?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77d46b24f0f7a362efd556", "question": "In the novel and movie \"Hitchhikers Guide to The Galaxy,\" what is the most important thing a hitchhiker can carry?", "answer": "A towel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7b", "question": "In what film is Bruce Willis' first scene backed by Al Green's \"Let's Stay Together\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddb2c6ce05a3942286d8f", "question": "What are the names of the Pac-Man ghost enemies?", "answer": "Plinky, Pinky, Inky and Clyde (AKA Pokey)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0c", "question": "What was the name of the shipwrecked boat on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "S.S. Minnow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d1", "question": "The song \"A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes\" was originally featured in what Disney film?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b395", "question": "What famous trials were held in 1692 and 1693?", "answer": "Salem witch trials", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892a", "question": "In Larry Niven's novel \"Ringworld\", what is the drug that extends human life to near immortality?", "answer": "Boosterspice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d979d08b8581f80b092aa", "question": "What name was given to the tropical cyclone that destroyed large parts of the Houston metropolitan area in the United States in August of 2017?", "answer": "Hurricane Harvey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392bb", "question": "Which sitcom was set in the offices of the fictional magazine \"Blush\"?", "answer": "Just Shoot Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93d856bd93ce3a4e5f6b7", "question": "In which type of chemical bonding are electrons shared between adjacent atoms?", "answer": "Covalent", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d7", "question": "What extinct subspecies of zebra had stripes in front but a plain brown hindquarters?", "answer": "The quagga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e77", "question": "During what war was \"The Iliad\" set?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a748", "question": "What island in California was once called Pelican Island?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd69fb66c0f9723ab15cb2e", "question": "Benazir Bhutto was the first female prime minister of which country?", "answer": "Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b491", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games in 1896?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4b68406d333868d34d6f2", "question": "Which British royal family changed its name from Saxe-Coburg-Gotha in 1917?", "answer": "Windsors", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b581", "question": "What year was the first iPad released?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85b", "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c123", "question": "What is the Binot-Simon Scale used to measure?", "answer": "Intelligence", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339840", "question": "In \"Monty Python And The Holy Grail\", what group demanded that Arthur bring them a shrubbery?", "answer": "The Knights who say Ni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a373", "question": "What is the capital of Germany?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5b466ce05a3942286e14", "question": "\"V-Bucks\" are the in-game currency for which famous videogame franchise?", "answer": "\"Fortnite\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa1c173838c5c8a417f1c", "question": "How much more blood does a pregnant woman's body contain?", "answer": "The amount can increase by as much as 50% or more.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c65", "question": "Steven Spielberg's first full feature film as director was released in what year?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9d", "question": "What Halle Berry movie is named for the password in the Marx Brothers' \"Horse Feathers\"?", "answer": "Swordfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74b", "question": "When graphed, the implicit curve equation produces what shape?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9380574a5ce6b56b823c", "question": "Who was the only man to knock out Muhammad Ali in a heavyweight title fight?", "answer": "Larry Holmes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894d", "question": "What William Golding novel tells the story of a group of boys cast away on a desert island?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b445", "question": "How old was Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, when he died in 1890?", "answer": "27", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c696", "question": "What US company invented fiberglass in 1938?", "answer": "Owens-Corning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c76e877e98cb977789ce", "question": "Which continent is home to the only egg-laying mammals in the world?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8e", "question": "Who was sued in 1999 by Rosa Parks after they used her name to title a hit song?", "answer": "OutKast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c672", "question": "What mission was the first successful manned mission to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a81", "question": "Edie Sedgwick was a protege of what artist?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febabf47e83c707845b20e9", "question": "What species holds the Guinness World Record for heaviest insect?", "answer": "Goliath beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339325", "question": "In the movie \"Monsters Inc.\", what are the monsters most scared of?", "answer": "Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b620e662d71a53651002", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Silent Spring,\" which describes the harmful effects of pesticides on the environment?", "answer": "Rachel Carson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a9", "question": "How did actor Humphrey Bogart die?", "answer": "Esophageal cancer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc76", "question": "Who was responsible for creating Reese's Peanut Butter Cups in 1928?", "answer": "H. B. Reese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b438", "question": "Which historical figure passed away on April 18, 1955?", "answer": "Albert Einstein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6cb", "question": "What gymnastic event often sees men performing the Iron Cross or Crucifix?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8ac5601dd7bf43be5e76a", "question": "Which type of fruit juice did Dole sell first?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339945", "question": "What is the last name of the three brothers part of the original Beach Boys?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38c", "question": "What is the second-highest mountain on Earth?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b271", "question": "What did \"Glamorous Glennis\" do on October 19, 1947?", "answer": "Broke the sound barrier for the first time", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f7", "question": "What is the name of Nintendo's first video game console?", "answer": "Color TV Game", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938c", "question": "What is Doc allergic to in the movie \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "Synthetics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba01", "question": "What nickname was given to baseball hall-of-famer Honus Wagner?", "answer": "Flying Dutchman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4da", "question": "What fruit comes in Navel and Blood variety?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7c", "question": "During what war was the novel \"For Whom the Bell Tolls\" set?", "answer": "Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2f", "question": "Christmas Island is a territory belonging to which country?", "answer": "Australia\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ad", "question": "The assassination of what country's Archduke led to World War I?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a835", "question": "What US state is the source of the Arkansas, Platte, and Rio Grande rivers?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c435", "question": "What is the only bone in the human body that doesn't connect with any other?", "answer": "Hyoid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ea", "question": "Who is the developer of the game series \"Gran Turismo\"?", "answer": "Polyphony Digital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e61b22f44c2d77a29c3f", "question": "What is Patty's last name in the 1978 film \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Simcox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a722", "question": "What cave found in New Mexico, is the deepest cave in the continental US?", "answer": "Lechuguilla Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32354fbf195a31e15d73ad", "question": "Which American comedian was born Benjamin Kubelsky?", "answer": "Jack Benny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7d", "question": "What is the common name for the Aurora Borealis?", "answer": "Northern lights", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea8025ff048f679a45ac18", "question": "What period did the Tyrannosaurus Rex live during?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339282", "question": "In season 14 of \"Big Brother\" what coach told Britney that she is so good because she is incapable of feeling emotion?", "answer": "Janelle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338944", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the name of the staff carried by Hermes?", "answer": "The Caduceus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774321284458f1d7854425", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ab", "question": "Which US city was author J. D .Salinger born in?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b698fb6c85e9e634ff49", "question": "What country's national flower is the Wattle?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a09020565ad31a57c796", "question": "What was the Statue of Liberty originally designed to commemorate?", "answer": "Freed enslaved people", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccb", "question": "What stadium hit do we owe to a pre-Civil War folk song and the Swedish dance band Rednex?", "answer": "Cotton Eye Joe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff516f0ff04d658268c92f7", "question": "Egyptian workers were often paid with a ration of what?", "answer": "Beer (It was so beloved in Ancient Egypt that it was an accepted form of currency.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067e76ff9c0647b50a807a", "question": "Who was awarded the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a3", "question": "What river was connected to Lake Erie by the Erie Canal?", "answer": "The Hudson River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabf", "question": "What did Eli Whitney invent?", "answer": "Cotton gin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc9", "question": "Which Apollo 11 astronaut did not set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Michael Collins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00d", "question": "What was the real first name of David Soul's \"Hutch\" on \"Starsky and Hutch\"?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d78", "question": "What movie features three tunnels named Tom, Dick, and Harry?", "answer": "The Great Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002415b4be4723ccac22176", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Thomas Harris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f1", "question": "What do you get by mixing ginger ale with grenadine and a cherry?", "answer": "A Shirley Temple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015df92fe83fe1f2a824b7b", "question": "Who was the first female surgeon in the U.S. Army?", "answer": "Mary Edwards Walker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66645a5bfecdd737e0868", "question": "What is the highest possible FICO score?", "answer": "850", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae2", "question": "A \"Tiercel\" is the traditional term for a male what?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339936", "question": "Who played Willie Scott in the movie \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\"?", "answer": "Kate Capshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23a", "question": "What Australian rock band release the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd72fe347d002c297e4bf", "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76f2aeec85e375820b2e3", "question": "Which two countries are on the southern border of Mexico?", "answer": "Guatemala and Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a7f58b6f5f79087132fb3f", "question": "Which religious figure is depicted in many of the tallest statues on Earth?", "answer": "Buddha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95b", "question": "What is the carambola fruit more commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Starfruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ca", "question": "What comedian is remembered for his saying \"Everybody wants ta get inta de act\"?", "answer": "Jimmy Durante", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a552fd3e1c6f9840ba319f", "question": "Which band released the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339905", "question": "In what movie does Jack Nicholson\u2019s character describe woman as men without \u201creason and accountability\u201d?", "answer": "As Good As It Gets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c4", "question": "Which UK politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ad", "question": "What natural disaster is measured on the Richter Scale?", "answer": "Earthquakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93d", "question": "What bird is the smallest living bird?", "answer": "Bee Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d3d42596a59cbdfbd39e", "question": "What was the name of the first computer search engine?", "answer": "Archie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f7", "question": "What is the street address of the White House?", "answer": "1600 Pennsylvania Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390dd", "question": "In the Winnie-the-Pooh stories what is Kanga\u2019s baby called?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b583e662d71a53650ffb", "question": "In which classic children's book does the protagonist only eat cabbage?", "answer": "\"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f50", "question": "What network has aired \"Shark Week\" every summer since 1988?", "answer": "The Discovery Channel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a887", "question": "What island was once called Van Diemen's Land?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0d", "question": "What fast food chain was founded by Colonel Harland Sanders?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00c", "question": "What two Orlando Magic teammates made their screen debuts in \"Blue Chips\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal and Anfernee Hardaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121b4f63c99d48cd169b0d", "question": "\"Astrolatry\" is the worship of what as deities?", "answer": "Celestial bodies -- People who practice astrolatry consider the sun, moon, stars and other celestial bodies as gods.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c5", "question": "What is Frank Whittle credited with inventing?", "answer": "Turbojet engine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d4", "question": "What part of the eye is damaged by glaucoma?", "answer": "The optic nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd8", "question": "Who originally sang the 1973 song that became a big Dixie Chicks hit in 2002?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fd", "question": "What element on the Periodic Table is represented by the symbol \"Hg\"?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938d", "question": "Where did Rocky Balboa keep his gym locker combination?", "answer": "In his hat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976a", "question": "What is the name of the clown in It?", "answer": "Pennywise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ba", "question": "Which planet orbits the Sun the quickest?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b22", "question": "What is the name of the little people in \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Munchkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e0", "question": "Which famous actress was born Vera Jane Palmer?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8f", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"The Door in the Floor\" based on?", "answer": "A Widow for One Year", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e6", "question": "What was the name of the 90's TV show starring Jamie Lee Curtis and comedian Richard Lewis?", "answer": "Anything But Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a906", "question": "What major river runs through Cairo?", "answer": "Nile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c0", "question": "As what type of beans are chickpeas also known as?", "answer": "Garbanzo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4aa", "question": "Which desert covers part of China and Mongolia?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfa", "question": "What movie is credited with popularizing the \"little black dress\"?", "answer": "Breakfast at Tiffany's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcc", "question": "What TV show did \"Trapper John, M.D.\" spin off from?", "answer": "M*A*S*H", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2bd", "question": "How many seasons were there of the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada2", "question": "Robert Leroy Parker was better known as who?", "answer": "Butch Cassidy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58be2d938faf425cf37add80", "question": "What automotive company produced car name the RX-7?", "answer": "Mazda", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c075", "question": "What is the common two word name for Yucca Brevifolia?", "answer": "Joshua Tree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25d36b63e5727cf5a4863", "question": "What is the name of 1992 hit single by the band \"Shakespears Sister\"?", "answer": "Stay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa5cb73838c5c8a417f2b", "question": "A quahog is what kind of sea creature?", "answer": "Clam (It is common along the Eastern coast of the American continent, from Prince Edward Island down to the Yucatan Peninsula.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dbbee748bb36357acdd8", "question": "What is the scientific name of the killer whale?", "answer": "Orcinus orca", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51a", "question": "What tart fruit has a sweet variety called \"Meyer\"?", "answer": "Lemon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffb", "question": "Who was the son of Saturn and Ops, and the husband of Juno?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c13", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the seventh plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Storms of fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb1", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Salty Dog?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b203", "question": "What metal item on the end of a kite string gave off the sparks in Benjamin Franklin's 1752 experiment?", "answer": "A key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51377ff04d658268c92db", "question": "What military award was established during the American Civil War?", "answer": "Senator Henry Wilson introduced a resolution on February 15, 1862 for an Army Medal of Honor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf55", "question": "This drink is made from espresso coffee, hot milk and chocolate?", "answer": "Mocha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1dd", "question": "What does the term \"A La Carte\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "According to the menu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc4206ce05a3942286f2d", "question": "What is the name of the ramrod in the television series \"Rawhide\"?", "answer": "Rowdy Yates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1a", "question": "What was the nickname of character Freddie Stubbs on the 1970's sitcom \"What's Happening!!\"?", "answer": "Rerun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d967709c1c34536e6eab", "question": "What does sonography use to make pictures of the inside of the body?", "answer": "Sound waves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4eb", "question": "Which US state's name begins but doesn't end with the letter A?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358d4b5db0d66a186cb560", "question": "From which South American country do the beers \"Brahma\" and \"Antarctica\" come?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec8", "question": "Mr. Giles French was a character on which US TV show in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Family Affair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e3", "question": "Grand Mesa is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ff", "question": "John Paul Jones' frigate was named \"Bonhomme Richard\", after whose pen name?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4e", "question": "The anniversary of the death of what magician is recognized as National Magic Day in the US?", "answer": "Harry Houdini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef928a6ce05a3942286e84", "question": "What was Led Zeppelin's original name?", "answer": "The New Yardbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be61", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8893ec223966ae8f8820", "question": "Which singer began her rise to superstardom actually as a dancer on a sketch-comedy television program?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez (she was a dancer on the Wayans Brothers' TV Show \"In Living Color\")", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a4", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600e0e381d348e9c6eed4815", "question": "How many people (military and civilians) in the Soviet Union died from World War II.", "answer": "Approximately 27 million people died as a result of the war, which represented 15% of the population of the country.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ded806d333868d34d71c", "question": "Who was the first Western explorer to reach China?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec5", "question": "What two future Munsters costarred in the TV show \"Car 54, Where Are You\"?", "answer": "Fred Gwynne and Al Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b44201dd7bf43be5e7bd", "question": "A sentence containing every letter in the alphabet is called what?", "answer": "Pangram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cde", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured John Travolta and Forest Whitaker?", "answer": "Battlefield Earth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a6", "question": "What continent includes Iran?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339359", "question": "What does the \"D.J.\" stand for in D.J. Tanner's name in the TV show \"Full House\"?", "answer": "Donna Jo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c201", "question": "Which country were the 1896 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a633", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peace Garden State\"?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966d", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", in which foreign country did the Simpsons appear on a game show?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede3b36ce05a3942286dd5", "question": "In what hotel does Ben rendezvous with Mrs. Robinson in \"The Graduate\"?", "answer": "The Taft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcd", "question": "What British pop group did Bryan Ferry lead after Brian Eno's 1973 departure?", "answer": "Roxy Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7b", "question": "What is the capital of Sierra Leone?", "answer": "Freetown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c9", "question": "In the military, what does the abbreviation G.I. stand for?", "answer": "Government Issue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c03", "question": "What psychologist's autobiography was titled \"Flashbacks\"?", "answer": "Timothy Leary", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd201ec223966ae8f88c2", "question": "How many visible cuts are there in the 2014 film \"Birdman\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c720fbde8045e48466be", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is the closest to Earth in size?", "answer": "Venus -- The two planets are nearly identical in size and mass, with Venus measuring at about 0.95 the size of Earth.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba4a9874c93a3298b2147", "question": "What year did Oliver Cromwell die?", "answer": "1658", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675ca32b59efe0e9417e95", "question": "The dragonfly has six legs but rarely does what?", "answer": "Walk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f980fa5fdd6dd25324f8", "question": "Who would use a mashie niblick?", "answer": "A golfer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab7", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Greece?", "answer": "Little owl", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae47", "question": "What were the Americans who supported the British during the American Revolution known as?", "answer": "Loyalists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b32362bbf195a31e15d73b8", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339322", "question": "In \"Home Alone\", what animal did Buzz keep as a pet?", "answer": "A tarantula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b66b", "question": "A Bloody Mary is a cocktail made with tomato juice and what type of alcohol?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339475", "question": "What was the name of the store Seymour works at in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "SavMart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab25", "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?", "answer": "Antananarivo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c360", "question": "Who famously said \"Dr. Livingstone, I presume?\" in 1872?", "answer": "H.M. Stanley", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c0e23c87fd04dd15e1f", "question": "What U.S. post office doesn't fly the American flag?", "answer": "B. Free Franklin Post Office in Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb17a7e83c707845b210d", "question": "What are the fuzzy ends of a dandelion called?", "answer": "Seed Heads", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b620", "question": "What company did Edwin Land found?", "answer": "Polaroid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338faa", "question": "Which author wrote \"If I Forget Thee, Jerusalem\"?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59da1c04f6756c9b30ba1500", "question": "Who was the star of the TV cooking show \"The Galloping Gourmet\"?", "answer": "Graham Kerr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b239", "question": "What royal subject married Grace Kelly?", "answer": "Rainier III of Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd7", "question": "What film introduced the fraternity Lambda Lambda Lambda?", "answer": "Revenge of the Nerds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa76", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943f", "question": "What song do the soldiers sing walking through the rubble of Hue in the movie Full Metal Jacket?", "answer": "The Mickey Mouse Club theme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acca", "question": "What city became capital of Cuba in 1519?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "history"}]